He's a cop who believes no one is above the law.
Above the Law is a action, crime, thriller film directed by Andrew Davis.
Nico Toscani is an Italian immigrant, American patriot, ex-CIA agent,
aikido specialist and unorthodox Chicago policeman.
He is as committed to his job as he is to his personalized brand
of justice—expert and thorough bone-crushing.
Nico Toscani, played by Steven Seagal.
Delores 'Jacks' Jackson, played by Pam Grier.
Kurt Zagon, played by Henry Silva.
Sara Toscani, played by Sharon Stone.
Detective Lukich, played by Ron Dean.
Tony Salvano, played by Daniel Faraldo.
Above the Law (also known as Nico: Above the Law, or simply Nico) is a 1988 American
action thriller film co-written, produced and directed by Andrew Davis.
It marked the film debut of Steven Seagal, who also produced the film and co-authored the story
alongside Davis, and stars Seagal alongside Pam Grier, Sharon Stone, Ron Dean and Henry Silva.
Seagal plays Nico Toscani, an ex-CIA agent, an Aikido specialist and a Chicago policeman who discovers a
conspiracy upon investigating a mysterious shipment of military explosives seized from a narcotics dealer.
The film originated after a successful screen test financed by Michael Ovitz,
leading to Seagal being offered a contract by Warner Bros.
It was set and filmed on location in Chicago, Davis’ hometown.
The film premiered in the United States on April 8, 1988, becoming a commercial
success despite mixed reviews, and launching Seagal's acting career.
Above the Law is regarded as the first American film
to feature Aikido in fight sequences.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, martial arts,
vietnam, central intelligence agency (cia), corruption.
The tone is intense.